# JOHN BERGSEN

A Technical Content Writer with five years of experience specializing in content development, brand messaging, UX writing, and product marketing. A proven track record of delivering high-impact content to clients to enhance web traffic and drive customer acquisitions.

San Francisco, CA 12345 johnbergsendi ex atnple.com (123)456-7890 Linked In | Portfolio

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **TECHNICAL CONTENT WRITER**

Energize Technology Inc., San Francisco, CA May 2020 - Present

- Led the development of marketing content for a suite of technology products generating over S30M in annual revenue, which included creating blogs, web copy, and digital marketing content to drive customer acquisition and increase market penetration
- Utilized knowledge of the technology industry to develop high-impact content for application development, UI design, and B2B technology solutions
- Increased website traffic by 250% by using SEO marketing strategics, link building campaigns to enhance web copy and blog posts

#### FREELANCE CONTENT WRITER

Self-Employed, San Francisco, CA June 2018 - May 2020

- Executed a wide variety of freelance content writing projects for clients, including web pages, blog posts, and product marketing copy
- ◆ Collaborated with client stakeholders to ensure consistent tone, voice, and brand messaging, resulting in a 95% client satisfaction rating on Upwork and Fiverr

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) English University of San Francisco, San Francisco, CA September 2014 - June 2018

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Technical Writing
- Content Development
- · Brand Messaging
- Product Marketing
- ♦ Web Copy

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Professional Technical Writing Certification, Technical Writer HQ, 2020
- UX Writing Certification, Udemy, 2020